

724.630.4370 joe@benscoter.design joebenscoter.com 713 Means Ave. Bellevue, PA

# **PROFILE**

With 5 years of product design experience building a B2B ecommerce platform, I am well equipped to craft complex business flows into systems that achieve business goals and that people enjoy using. From defining specifications and prototyping to launching and refining, I am excited to collaborate with your team to build the future.

# **EXPERIENCE**

JANUARY 2017 - PRESENT

**Lead Product Designer & Product Owner** - eParts Services IIc (alpscontrols.com spinoff)

Collaborate with other team leads and stakeholders to establish product vision, road map, and quarterly goals and work with the team to achieve those goals. Design new features and new iterations of current features while mentoring a junior designer. Collaborate with developers to see designs through to completion and release. Highlight projects include launching an ecommerce platform for a fortune 100 company, designing a robust order history reporting system, and building out a pattern library.

JANUARY 2015 - DECEMBER 2016

UI/UX Designer & Developer - alpscontrols.com

Worked directly with our development team and owners to both design and develop a complete code rewrite and visual redesign of the core customer facing B2B ecommerce platform. This included user research, persona creation, usability testing, competitor analysis, and new feature conception. In designing the platform, I used everything from paper sketches to high fidelity mockups with reusable components based on atomic design principles. I also created our frontend build process, coded semantic HTML, and structured our CSS using the BEMIT model.

**NOVEMBER 2016 - PRESENT** 

Web Design & Development - Contract Work

Designed and developed the front-end of the mobile responsive payment processing and membership management dashboard that powers eServices PaaS. Currently building transaction reporting components using Vue.js. For another client, I designed and aided front-end development of a marketing website for a Kickstarter campaign: taikocardgame.com.

MAY 2014 - DECEMBER 2014

Web Developer Intern- alpscontrols.com

Translated web pages from asp classic to php, created a customer notification system, created a page for customers to view all their current order tracking info at a glance.

## **EDUCATION**

**Penn State University** 

Information Sciences and Technology (B.S.) Business (Minor)

### **SKILLS**

High Fidelity Mockups
Wire Frames
Style Guide Development
Usability Testing
Ethnographic Interviews
Personas
Agile Development
Semantic HTML
CSS (BEM, ITCSS, Sass)
JavaScript
Vue.js
Critical Thinking

#### **TOOLS**

Figma
Adobe Xd
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe Photoshop
Invision
Build Tools (NPM, Gulp)
Visual Studio
Azure DevOps
Git